Shaw'ne Bullard

Los Angeles, CA 90003 shawnebullard8_dx2@indeedemail.com (760) 217-2440

An Accountant with over 15 years of experience in the accounting industry. Knowledge of corporate accounting procedures, financial statement preparation, general ledger activity, budget preparation & analysis, bank reconciliation, accounts payables and receivables, payroll, fixed asset, tax preparation, and audit procedures.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Sr. Accountant

Teledyne Controls (Manufacturing) - El Segundo, CA July 2013 to Present

- Prepare analysis of daily cash positioning and 5 week cash forecast
- · Oversee and manage day to day function of accounts receivable AR Staff; credit hold order releases
- Manage the process for cash applications
- Actively manage outstanding account receivables through payment agreements, collections, and review of credit limits.
- Review, evaluate, and release orders from backlog to production.
- Oversee the credit application processes; is responsible for gathering and analyzing appropriate financial data to recommend appropriate credit limits and credit terms.
- Forecasts collections activity by account as necessary to aid in forecasting cash flow and impact on revenue recognition.
- Ensure that cash, credit card, wire and lockbox transactions are posted correctly to the accounts receivable sub-ledger.
- Review aging reports with staff to identify delinquent accounts considered to be uncollectable ensuring maximum efforts have been taken before assigning bad credit status to account.
- Forecasts collections activity by account as necessary to aid in forecasting cash flow and impact on revenue recognition.
- Builds and manages relationships with customers and sales teams.
- Prepare weekly AR Aging and key metrics reporting for management.
- Assist with month, quarter, and year-end close
- Support special projects or financial analysis when needed by management
- Reconcile bank accounts, ledgers, reports, and financial records
- Participated in quarterly and year-end audit and interacted with auditors
- Create accounts receivable yearly business plan
- File monthly, quarterly, yearly sales and used tax
- FOB shipping quarterly analysis

Sr. Accountant

CMH Records, Inc (Music Production & Distribution) - Los Angeles, CA

November 2007 to July 2013

- Supervise accounting team with daily workflow
- Coach, assist and develop A/P and A/R team including performance evaluations.
- Review AP team entries for auditing requirements; compliance, receiving, approvals, GL coding, and expense allocation
- Approve and release reviewed vouchers for payment
- Ensure timely payments of vendor invoices and maintain accurate vendor records
- Assist A/P team with vendor inquiries, unresolved invoices due to lack of receiving, invoice discrepancies and research invoices received with no PO's in place
- Approve weekly check runs, ACH transfers and large volume quarterly royalty check runs
- Prepared, reviewed, and approved federal 1099 Tax Returns for vendors
- Created daily, weekly sales and cash reports for management
- Reconciled vendor statements and handled payment complaints or discrepancies
- Produced monthly accounting reports and financial statements
- · Analyzed and reconciled Accounts Payable and Accounts Receivable at month-end
- Prepared monthly bank reconciliation
- Prepared and record journal entries for month-end close
- Manage the company's corporate card program

Credit Collection Analyst/ Staff Accountant

Universal Metro, Inc (Construction) April 2004 to November 2007

- · Obtained revenue and paid invoices by verifying and completing payable and receivable transactions
- Paid invoices by verifying transaction information; scheduling and preparing disbursements; obtaining authorization of payment.
- Obtained revenue by verifying transaction information; computing charges and refunds; preparing and mailing invoices; identifying delinquent accounts and insufficient payments.
- Collect revenue by reminding delinquent accounts; notifying customers of insufficient payments Maintained accounting ledgers by posting account transactions
- Verified accounts by reconciling statements and transactions
- Resolves account discrepancies by investigating documentation; issuing stop payments, payments, or adjustments Prepared year-end 1099's and other miscellaneous information
- Prepared, reviewed and approved tax return preparation and submittal for oversees VAT and 1099s
- Manage accounts payable and accounts receivable, including invoicing and collecting payments from clients
- Responsible for daily accounting operations, including transaction and payment processing and account/bank reconciliations
- Work closely with the Chief Financial Officer on budget preparation
- Run month-end processes including producing financial statements
- · Maintain current business forecast and cash flow
- Maintain internal control systems and assist with internal audits
- Organized and maintained personnel files, work schedules, and payroll

Education

Masters in Accounting specialization in Fraud Management

Colorado State University-Global Campus

May 2015 to March 2016

Bachelors in Accounting

University of Phoenix-Southern California Campus

September 2009 to December 2012

Skills

- General Ledger Accounting
- Journal Entries
- Bank Reconciliation
- Financial Statement Preparation
- Account Reconciliation
- Account Analysis
- QuickBooks
- Credit Analysis
- Financial Analysis
- Office Management